你正被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
A machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know, because I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror,
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything...
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people,
像你一样的普通人
people like you,
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
但不管是被害人还是行凶者
But, victim or perpetrator,
只要你的号码被列出来
if your number's up,
我们就会找到你
we'll find you.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第21集
Person of Interest S01E21 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-
当你找到你在这个世上的羁绊
When you find that one person who connects you to the world,
你就变了
you become someone different...
变得更好
Someone better.
而当她被人从你身边夺去
When that person is taken from you...
等我
Wait for me.
那你又会变得怎样
What do you become then?
您没事吧  先生
Are you okay, mister?
您怎么了
What happened to you?
我大概是辞职了
I think I quit my job.
下一站  新罗歇尔
Next stop, New Rochelle.
《应力性骨折中对钛的运用》
早啊  芬奇
Morning, Finch.
你来得真早  里瑟先生
You're off to an early start, Mr. Reese.
我想取悦一下老板啊
Maybe I'm trying to impress the boss.
你该先打个电话给我
Should have called first.
今天没有行程安排
As it stands, our docket is clear.
没有号码吗
We don't have a number?
你好像挺失望
You sound disappointed.
有点惊讶
A little surprised.
在纽约居然无人身处危险
No one in New York is in danger
无人策划害人
or planning to hurt someone?
就算有  也仅是在心中暗想
If they are, they're keeping it to themselves.
总之  我认为你应该放假
Anyway, I think you've earned some time off.
特别是今天
Especially today.
难道你以为我不知道吗
Or did you think I didn't know?
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气  走吧
You're welcome. Now go.
随便做些你在外边做的事吧
Do whatever you do when you're not here.
你不知道我在外边做些什么吗
You don't know what that is?
我尊重你的隐私  约翰
I respect your privacy, John.
显而易见啊
Obviously.
>搜索社保号码
>000-10-7821
>搜索中
>发现目标  加纳  凯伦
>搜索车管局数据库
>加纳  凯伦 和 000-10-7821
>搜索中
>发现照片
>在新窗口打开
炮八进六
Cannon 8 to 6.
马二进三
Horse 2 to 3.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你说呢  韩
You tell me, Han.
据我对你的了解  约翰
As I recall, John,
你从不做任何没把握的事
you don't make any move you're not sure of.
今天不用工作吗
You're not working today?
老板放我假了
My boss gave me the day off.
今天是我生日
It's my birthday.
生日快乐
Sheng ri kuai le.
谢谢
Thank you.
收到礼物了吗
Did you get any gifts?
收到一件
One.
钥匙
A key?
开什么的
To what?
问得好
Good question.
卡特警探
Detective Carter.
唐纳利特工
Special Agent Donnelly.
对神秘男子的追查进展如何
How goes your hunt for our mystery man?
我正是为此而来
That's why I'm here.
我保证过会通知你调查的最新进展
I promised I'd keep you in the loop on our investigation.
是这样  我们在调查一伙数月前
So... we'd been looking into a smuggling ring that was
解散的走私团伙
broken up a couple of months back.
团伙头领可能在中情局内部有人
The leader was suspected of having CIA ties,
不过他在被起诉前跑了
but he skipped before he could be charged.
我记得
I recall.
我们认为神秘男子替他干过活
Yeah, well, we think your guy was working for him.
鉴证组在一辆烧毁的汽车后备箱中
CSU found prints and some carbonized blood,
发现一名走私成员的尸体
along with the body of a member of the ring,
以及部分指纹和炭化血迹
in the trunk of a burned-out car.
他们在血液检测时
When they ran the blood,
发现其DNA跟2011年
they got a DNA hit on a cold case up
新罗歇尔的一起悬案吻合
in New Rochelle from 2011.
什么悬案
What kind of cold case?
疑似凶杀案
Suspected homicide.
一个叫彼得・阿恩特的房地产开发商
Real estate developer named Peter Arndt.
房地产开发商
Real estate developer?
对  阿恩特欠了一屁股债
Yeah. Arndt was up to his eyeballs in debt.
亏掉了他投资者的钱
Lost his investors' money.
我们认为是其中一个投资者
We think one of them had him taken out,
雇了那神秘男子干的
hired your guy to do the job.
他在现场留下了痕迹
And he made some mistakes.
新罗歇尔多半有人知道内幕
Now someone in New Rochelle has to know something
那我们就快接近了
and then we'll be close.
接近什么
Close to what?
那名男子的真实身份
Finding out who this man really is.
好吧  谢谢你来通知我
Well, thank you for the update.
来帮个忙如何
How'd you like to assist?
帮忙
Assist?
去一趟新罗歇尔
Up in New Rochelle.
我确实很想帮忙  不过
I would love to, but--
考虑一下吧
Think about it.
毕竟  因为你  我们才会注意到他
I mean, you're the reason we're onto this guy.
你理应分享抓获他的功劳
You should be a part of taking him down.
-我回头答复你  -谢谢
- I'll let you know. - Thanks.
喂
Yeah.
你好  警探
Hello, detective?
我有事要找你商量
There's something I need to discuss with you.
是嘛
Yeah?
我也正好有事找你
I got something for you too.
你居然也会喝啤酒吃烤肉
Never pegged you as the cues-and-brews type.
所以我更要选这里了  警探
All the more reason to come here, detective.
行为如可预期
Once we become predictable,
更易遭受攻击
we become vulnerable.
好吧
If you say so.
您需要点什么
What can I get you?
苏打水吧
Club soda for me.
-好的  -谢谢
- Okay. - Thanks.
你在电话里说  有事找我
When I called, you said you had something for me.
你知道一件新罗歇尔的案子吗
You know about a case up in New Rochelle?
看样子你知道
I'll take that as a "yes."
联调局在现场找到了你搭档的DNA
FBI linked your partner's DNA to a crime scene.
肯定是唐纳利探员吧
Agent Donnelly, no doubt.
他想让我同去
He wants me along for the ride.
或许这不是什么坏事
Perhaps that wouldn't be such a bad thing?
怎么说
How do you mean?
如果有任何证据会威胁到我们共同的朋友
If there was any evidence that threatened our mutual friend,
我确信你会比唐纳利先找到的
I'm confident that you would find it before Donnelly would.
你是在建议我干扰联邦调查吗
Are you suggesting I obstruct a federal investigation?
当然  如何处理那些证据完全是
Of course what you did with that evidence would be
你个人的决定
entirely your concern.
你找我什么事
You wanted to talk to me about something.
不是什么大不了的事
It was nothing important.
等你回来了我们再聊
We'll talk again when you get back.
感谢请客
Thanks for the drink.
还要点什么
Anything else?
不用了  麻烦结账
No, I'll just take the check, please.
好的
Okay.
给
Here you go.
谢谢
Thank you.
2011年2月
我是洁西卡  你错过我喽
This is Jessica, you missed me.
请留言
Leave a message.
需要帮助吗
Do you need any help?
是的
Yes.
我在找人
I'm looking for someone.
一名护士
A nurse.
洁西卡・阿恩特
Jessica Arndt.
我是她的老朋友
I'm an old friend.
她可能不在这儿上班了
She might not work here anymore.
她总说想换个环境
She was always talking about moving away.
很抱歉告诉您这个消息
I'm sorry to have to tell you this.
洁西卡死于一场车祸
Jessica died in a car accident.
就在两个月前
About two months ago.
她说她会等的
She said she would wait.
我很遗憾
I'm so sorry.
如果你想联系她的家人
I think I have her husband's number here,
我好像有她丈夫的电话
if you wanted to reach out.
对不起
Sorry.
她离开公寓了吗
Has she left the apartment?
还没
Not yet.
你干嘛对这个感兴趣啊   芬奇
Hey, what's your interest in this broad anyway, Finch?
不关你的事
It's not your concern.
盯紧目标就行了
Just keep an eye out.
凯伦・加纳
Karen Garner.
她因为身份盗窃及使用空头支票而被通缉
She's wanted for identity theft, passing bad checks.
通缉令从底特律发出
Warrant's out of Detroit.
这姑娘可是重罪犯
Your girl's a felon.
是的  我知道她违法的问题  警探
Yes, I'm aware of her apparent troubles with the law, detective.
但我更担心她会有危险
But I'm more concerned that she may be in danger.
为什么这么想
What makes you think that?
凯伦・加纳是个化名
Karen Garner is an alias.
这个名字只出现了三个月
It's only been around for three months.
她没有信用记录
She has no credit history,
只有需要工作才离开公寓
she only leaves the apartment to go to work
出门时总是不停回头察看
and she's constantly looking over her shoulder.
好像她在隐藏自己
Sounds like she's hiding out.
或者说在跑路  更贴切
Or on the run, more likely.
也许她想低调点  以便筹划什么事
Maybe she's laying low, trying to plan something.
是啊  说不定她是个犯罪高手呢
Yes, perhaps she's a master criminal.
但也许她只是一名受惊的女人
But maybe she's just a scared woman
努力躲开威胁她的人
trying to stay a step ahead of her abuser.
好吧
Yeah, right.
我还想问你点事情
Let me ask you something, though.
干嘛要我办这差  你家神奇小子呢
Why am I planted out here instead of wonder boy?
里瑟先生另有安排
Mr. Reese is otherwise engaged.
你绝对不准为此事联系他  警探
And you are not to contact him regarding this matter, detective.
我们俩自己处理这件事
You and I will handle this ourselves.
没有新信息
卡特警探  欢迎来到新罗歇尔
Detective Carter, welcome to New Rochelle.
很高兴你接受了我的邀请
Glad to see you took me up on my offer.
目前掌握的情况如下
Here's what we know.
阿恩特一直在反复折腾投资者的钱
Arndt was playing it fast and loose with his investors' money.
最终因地产投资失败和赌博恶习全输光了
He ended up losing it on bad land deals and a gambling habit.
由于还不起信用卡
When he exhausted his line of credit,
他不得不从臭名昭著的贷款人手里借钱
he was forced to take money from less reputable lenders.
高利贷
Loan sharks.
他的赛马经纪人交待了两个人
His bookie gave us the name of a couple local guys
是他介绍给阿恩特的  我们正在核实
he introduced Arndt to, and we're checking it out.
上面说他已婚
Says he was married.
"妻子已故"
"Wife deceased."
她怎么了
What happened to her?
车祸
In a car accident.
阿恩特失踪前两个月发生的事
Two months before Arndt went missing.
严重车祸
Bad one.
她死了  他侥幸逃生
She was killed, he nearly was.
不过至此  阿恩特还是彻底潦倒了
But anyway, by that point, Arndt was completely under water.
出院没多久  他就失踪了
Shortly after he left the hospital, he went missing.
他们找到尸体了吗
They find a body?
没有  但鉴于发现的血量
No, but given the amount of blood spilled,
阿恩特不太可能还活着
it's doubtful Arndt survived.
听上去不像那家伙的做事风格
Doesn't sound like my guy's MO.
他通常很会掩饰自己的痕迹
He usually covers his tracks.
所以我们认为这是他的第一份活
That's another reason we think it was his first job.
现场一团糟  很血腥
It was messy, violent.
可能他本以为小菜一碟
Probably figured it would be easy,
结果发现不得不徒手苦战
then found out he had a fight on his hands.
我们找到了其中一个放高利贷的
We located one of the loan sharks.
你和本地警探谈过了吗
Did you talk to the local detectives?
还没  我有他们的资料
No, I had their files sent over.
我想和他们谈谈
I'd like to speak with them.
好的没问题
Sure. Great.
一有发现就通知我
Let me know if you find out anything.
会的
Will do.
有什么情况  警探
Anything yet, detective?
有  她在上班的路上
Yep. Our girl's on her way to work.
你说得没错
And you're right.
这女人是被吓得够呛
Someone's got this girl spooked.
我得跟踪她到什么时候
How long am I gonna have to tail her?
跟踪到我们找出她在躲谁
Long enough for me to identify who she's hiding from.
你有没有看到一个女的经过
Hey, did you see a woman come through here?
有  她问我借用后面的厕所来着
Yes, she asked to use the bathroom in the back.
警探
Detective?
等等
Hang on.
如果容我来猜测一下
So if I were to speculate as to the reason
你气喘吁吁的原因  警探
for your labored breathing, detective--
我跟丢了
I lost her.
果然如此
That would be it.
接下来怎么办
What do you want me to do?
回去当你的警察吧
Go back to your day job.
剩下的我来接手
I'll handle it from here.
您需要什么吗
What can I get you?
我来打听点事情
Just some information.
我昨晚来过
I was in here last night and
好像看到我邻居在这儿工作
I thought I saw my neighbor working here--
-凯伦・加纳  -没错  是她
- Karen Garner? - Yeah, that's right.
我路过这里
I was passing by again,
看看能不能碰到她
I thought I'd see if I could catch her.
她一般都在  不过今天请假了
Normally you would but she called out today.
那我下次再来吧
Another time then.
肯定能遇着
I'm sure I'll see her around.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我无意中听到了你在酒吧说的话
I couldn't help overhear your conversation at the bar.
你是凯伦・加纳的朋友吗
You're friends with Karen Garner?
只是点头之交
Well, more of an acquaintance, actually.
我叫布拉德・詹宁斯  联邦法警
Brad Jennings, US Marshals Service.
凯伦有什么麻烦吗  警官
Is Karen in some kind of trouble, Deputy?
凯伦・加纳  又名
Karen Garner, also known as
萨拉・阿特金斯  是名通缉犯
Sarah Atkins, is a wanted fugitive.
我正在找她
I'm trying to locate her.
不好意思  我不知道怎么帮你
Sorry, I don't know how I could help you.
我听你说  你跟她是邻居
Well, I thought I heard you say you were neighbors.
是的  没错
Yes, you did.
那请把你的住址告诉我  怎么称呼你
So maybe you could tell me where you live, Mr.--
不好意思  警官  我不想牵扯这事
I'm sorry, Deputy, I prefer not to get involved.
我没想牵扯到你
I'm not asking you to get involved.
把地址告诉我就好
I'm just trying to get your address.
如果你愿意也可以跟我去局里说
Now, if you prefer, we can do this down at the field office.
你好  哈罗德
Hello, Harold.
我是斯蒂尔斯警探  集团犯罪科
Detective Stills-- Organized Crime.
你问话的这人是我的线人
This guy you're talking to is my CI.
他是个秘密线人
He's a Confidential Informant?
还是已故黑帮头目莫雷蒂的洗钱人
And money launderer for the late Don Moretti.
我有话要问他
Hey, I've got some questions for him.
你的接近很可能会暴露他的身份
You were risking his cover by even approaching him.
我们走
Let's go.
他想干嘛
What did he want?
问我几个问题罢了
Just to ask me some questions.
真巧  我也有问题要问你  哈罗德
Funny, I've got a few of those for you too, Harold.
这么说你一直在跟踪我吗
So am I to assume that you were following me?
我想更重要的问题是
I think the bigger question is...
你是抛下我在独自行动吗
are you working a case without me?
我恐怕这案子对你来说  会有些敏感
I feared that, with this case, you had certain sensitivities.
因此最好别让你参与
I thought it best to let you sit it out.
有什么好敏感的
What kind of sensitivities?
她名叫  或者说她的假名叫
Her name-- or at least her aliases...
凯伦・加纳  以及萨拉・阿特金斯
are Karen Garner and Sarah Atkins.
她因为身份盗窃及使用空头支票
She has outstanding warrants for identity theft
遭到警方通缉
and passing bad checks,
不过我觉得她不是行凶者
but I don't think she's a potential perpetrator.
我认为她应该在躲避某人
I believe that she's on the run from someone.
躲避谁
Who?
很可能是她亲近的人
Likely someone she was close to.
我刚造出这台机器的时候
When I was first building the machine,
有些号码总是不停跳出来
I kept seeing the same numbers come up--
每隔一周  一个月或六个月
a week, a month, six months apart.
通常是女性
Usually women.
开始我以为是机器弄错了
At first I thought it was a mistake.
怎么会有人受到如此频繁的威胁
How could anyone's life be repeatedly threatened?
然后我意识到
And then I realized
她们是跟威胁自己生命的人住在一起
they were living with the person who would eventually kill them.
我一直在调查她的真实身份
I've been working to uncover who she really is.
这会帮我们确认威胁
It might help us identify the threat.
把她的地址发给我
Send me her address and
我们回头再讨论我的敏感问题
we'll finish discussing my sensitivities later.
你好  凯伦
Hello, Karen.
还是你更喜欢萨拉这个名字
Or do you prefer Sarah?
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
想帮助你的人
Someone who wants to help you.
你是警察吗
You a cop?
不是
No.
但我知道你在躲避某个人
But I know you're running from someone.
他是谁
Who is it?
男友吗
Boyfriend?
前男友吗
Ex-boyfriend?
丈夫吗
Husband?
丈夫
Husband.
我最后问你一遍
I'm going to ask you one last time.
你是谁
Who are you?
我叫约翰
My name's John.
我会救人于危难之境
And I help people out of tough situations.
那你知道我什么处境
What do you know about my situation?
我知道你处境糟到逼你逃离你的家
I know it was bad enough for you to leave your home,
你的生活  你的一切
your life, everything.
我还知道你得不停地逃  凯伦
And I know you'll have to keep running, Karen...
除非有人制止他
If nobody stops him.
萨拉
It's Sarah.
我名叫萨拉
My name is Sarah.
如果我说  你不用再逃了  萨拉
What if I said you could stop running, Sarah?
我会说你不了解我丈夫
I'd say you don't know my husband.
里瑟先生  凯伦的化名萨拉・阿特金斯
Mr. Reese, I traced Karen's former alias --Sarah Atkins
在芝加哥租公寓时使用过
to a Chicago apartment where she was living.
房东说她付房租账单上用的是另一个名字
Building manager said paid rent using checks with a different name.
他正把其中一张发给我
He's sending me one of them now.
萨拉・詹宁斯
Sarah Jennings.
詹宁斯  他是她的丈夫
Jennings -- He's her husband.
他是那法警
He's the Marshal.
你怎么知道的
How did you know that?
这不重要
That's not important.
重要的是我们能帮助你
What's important is we can help you.
-我们  -我有位同事
- We? - I have a colleague
他会在我去解决问题时照顾你
who will watch over you while I take care of things.
你得待在这里
We need you to stay here.
你要去做什么
What is it you're gonna do?
让你从此不必再担惊受怕
Make it so you don't have to be afraid anymore.
这是我们关于彼得・阿恩特的全部资料
That's everything we have on Peter Arndt.
多谢
Thanks.
这案子看上去手法专业吗  警探
Did this look like a professional hit to you, detective?
很难说
It's hard to say.
一般的雇佣谋杀可不像这个样子
We don't get a lot of contract killings up this way.
但这个阿恩特欠了一群危险分子的债
But this guy Arndt owed a lot of money to some dangerous people.
这是什么
And this?
阿恩特和他妻子的撞车事故报告
Accident report from a car crash Arndt and his wife were in.
单一车辆事故
Single car.
丈夫为躲避一头鹿急转弯
Husband swerved to avoid a deer.
妻子遇难
Wife was killed.
无常的是
It's a hell of a thing.
在这种车祸中幸存下来
Guy survives a crash like that
偏偏两个月后又出事了
only to get taken out two months later.
我得接个电话
I got to take this.
谢谢你
Thank you.
2011年2月
没有新信息
No new messages.
已存信息  请按九
To listen to saved messages, press 9.
是我  洁西卡
It's me. Jessica, I mean.
我都不知道你还会不会查看这个号码的信息
I don't even know if you check this number.
我想跟你聊聊
I need to talk.
你吓我一跳
You scared me.
你在跟谁通话
Who are you calling?
没谁
Nobody.
有意思
That's funny.
听上去你刚刚在跟某人通话
It sounded like you were calling somebody.
洁西卡・阿恩特
Jessica Arndt.
很漂亮的姑娘
Pretty girl.
当场死亡
Dead on the scene.
车辆翻滚造成头部被钝器所伤
Blunt force head injury from the rollover.
没系安全带
No seat belt.
你还留着她的X光片吗
Do you still have her x-rays?
阿恩特
Arndt.
就是这个
There we go.
你的报告中  检查到两处先前的骨折
In your report, you identified two previous fractures--
手腕骨折和肋骨断裂
A broken wrist and cracked rib.
我能看看吗
May I?
这是螺旋形骨折吗
Is that a spiral fracture?
我想是的
I suppose it is.
这种伤势得要手腕被强力扭转
She'd get that from having her wrist twisted hard
而不是被砸伤  对吧
as opposed to falling on it, right?
-过来  -你弄疼我了
- Come here. - You're hurting me.
还有件事
One other thing.
你把她的死因列为
You listed her cause of death as...
钝器击伤头部
Blunt force trauma to the head
和颈部扭伤
and a broken neck.
我是这么说的
As I said.
前侧安全气囊全都展开的情况下
Could someone suffer those kinds of injuries
人有可能会受伤至此吗
if the car's front and side air bags deployed?
一般不会  但是身体
Not likely, but a body is,
在那种撞击下易受严重外伤
subjected to extreme forces in a crash like that.
有没有可能她在
Is it possible she could
事故前就有了这些伤
have had these injuries before the accident?
你伤到我胳膊了
You're hurting my arm.
给我回来
Get back here!
不 不
No, no.
宝贝  宝贝
Baby. Baby.
洁西
Jess.
警探  我不知道你在曼哈顿经常处理的
Detective, I don't know what cases you're used to seeing
是什么案子  但在这里
down in Manhattan, but up here,
我面对最多的是车祸
car crashes account for most of my business.
有可能性  不代表就有可信性
Just because something's possible doesn't mean it's probable.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
我是卡特
Carter.
警探  我现在要去见阿恩特最亲近的家人
Detective, I'm heading up to speak with Arndt's closest family--
他的岳母
his mother-in-law.
看看她对他的财产危机有何了解
See if she knew anything about his money problems.
把地址发给我  在那儿碰头
Send me the address. I'll meet you there.
好的  马上
All right. Will do.
我在监视萨拉的公寓
I'm watching Sarah's apartment
同时在追踪她的手机定位  里瑟先生
and I'm tracking the GPS on her phone, Mr. Reese.
我还发现她丈夫的一些新资料
I've also discovered some new information about her husband.
据丹佛公务档案数据库的记录
According to the Denver Public Records Database,
詹宁斯曾因滥用职权两次被起诉
Jennings was sued twice for excessive use of force on the job.
两次起诉都被撤销
Both cases were dismissed.
他伪造了萨拉的拘捕令
He falsified the warrants on Sarah.
编造指控  利用整个美国法警部门
Trumped up the charges to enlist the entire US Marshal Service
帮他跟踪妻子
in helping him stalk his wife.
所以她只得一直逃亡
That's why she can't stop running.
只有一种方法能对付这种
Only one way to deal with guys like this,
在外装君子  回家变禽兽的东西
guys who hide who they really are until they get home.
你要干什么  里瑟先生
What will you do, Mr. Reese?
让他见识见识真正的魔鬼
Show 'em what a real monster looks like.
联邦法警局
公正  诚信  服务
警探  你叫什么来着
Detective... what was it?
斯蒂尔斯
Stills?
你改变主意同意我询问
You have a change of heart about me quest --
你的同事知道你来此的原因吗
Your fellow deputies know why you're here?
为了追踪你惊慌失措的妻子
Chasing your terrified wife?
再敢找她麻烦  我就要你的命
If you come after her again... I will kill you.
谁也救不了你
No one will be able to protect you from me.
明白了吗
Do you understand?
失去信号连接
芬奇  我们得把萨拉带到更安全的地方
Finch, we're gonna want to move Sarah to a safer location.
同意
Agreed.
或许之后你能帮我领悟一下
And then maybe you can explain the wisdom of antagonizing an
砸翻执法机关的个中深意
entire law enforcement agency.
里瑟先生  我们有麻烦了
Mr. Reese, we have a problem.
你好
Hi.
请给我一张去纽黑文的单程票
One way to New Haven, please.
好的  请出示身份证明
Sure. Just need photo ID.
谢谢
Thank you.
有问题吗
Is something wrong?
站住
Stop right there!
趴下
Get down on the ground!
凯伦・加纳  我们有你的拘捕令
Karen Garner, we have a warrant for your arrest!
嫌犯已被拘  在20轨处
Suspect in custody, track 20.
什么事  警探
Yes, detective.
我在无线电上听到你们追踪的女人被捕了
I just heard on the radio your girl got popped.
就在火车站
Down at the train station.
他们已经通知法警了
They picked her up on a Marshal's BOLO.
她现在在哪里
Where is she now?
可能还在那里
Probably still there.
法警去接她之前交警会暂时扣押她
Transit cops will hold her till the marshals can pick her up.
谢了  警探
Thanks, detective.
得赶快赶到车站去
Have to get to the train station.
我们来晚了  詹宁斯已经接走她了
We're too late. Jennings already picked her up.
他的丑行已曝露
With his cover blown,
不能通过官方途径带她回家
he can't take her home through official channels.
他会让她消失  芬奇
He's gonna make her disappear, Finch.
我们得找到她
We need to get to her.
我有办法了
I may have a way.
政府车辆现在都有
Government vehicles now have
接入因特网的移动热点
mobile hotspots for Internet access--
比如这个
Like this one.
包括法警的车辆吗
That include Marshal vehicles?
是的
Yes.
所以我可以进入他们的网络
So I can get into their network.
根据行踪判断出哪辆车是詹宁斯的
The trick will be figuring out which vehicle is Jennings'.
是这辆
That's him.
西城高速公路
West Side highway.
他要带她出城
He's taking her out of the city.
出去
Get out.
你说什么
Excuse me?
放下笔记本  哈罗德
Leave the laptop now, Harold.
然后出去
And get out.
您女儿真漂亮
Your daughter was so beautiful.
谢谢
Thank you.
你们俩亲近吗
Were you two close?
非常亲近
Very.
我们几乎每天都聊天
We spoke most every day.
你说想问几个关于彼得的问题
So you said you had some questions about Peter?
是的  夫人
Yes, ma'am.
在他失踪前
Prior to his disappearance,
您是否发现您女婿有财务上的困难
were you aware of your son-in-law's financial difficulties?
没有
No.
彼得有份好工作
Peter had a good job.
颇能养家
He was a good provider.
据我们了解
Based on our information,
他的各项负债总额超过三百万美元
he owed more than $3 million to various entities.
洁西卡提到过
Jessica once mentioned
他们遇到了困难
that they were going through a rough patch.
但是彼得正在力挽乾坤
But that Peter was turning things around.
那是在事故前夕
That was just before the accident.
失陪一下
Excuse me.
你说洁西卡告诉你
When you said Jessica told you
他们遇到了困难
"They were going through a rough patch,"
她说的是钱  还是她和彼得的感情
was she talking about money, or her and Peter?
不
No.
洁西卡和彼得婚姻很美满
Jessica and Peter had a good marriage.
他们是有些问题  任何夫妻都有  但是
I mean, they had problems, like any married couple
警探  出来一下好吗
Detective. See you a minute?
刚接到电话  那个西装男
I just got a call that a guy in a suit
在下城区分局袭击了四名法警
assaulted four deputy marshals in their downtown field office.
等等  你说什么
Wait. What?
是啊  我现在过去跟进情况
I know. I'm heading back down there to follow up.
你留在这里和那位母亲沟通好吗
Do you mind wrapping things up with the mother?
似乎没戏
It looks like a dead end.
没问题
Sure.
卡特警探
Detective Carter.
那四法警事件是怎么回事
What's this about an incident with four deputy Marshals?
情况在我掌握之中
I've got it under control.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
因为看起来可并非如此
'Cause it doesn't sound like it.
我确定  警探
Yes, detective.
你在新罗歇尔的调查怎么样了
So how is your New Rochelle investigation going?
唐纳利目前还没有发现
Donnelly hasn't found anything so far,
不过似乎我有
but I think I have.
我认为阿恩特杀了他的妻子并掩盖了罪行
Yeah, I think Arndt killed his wife and covered it up.
是你们喜欢介入的类型
The kind of thing you guys usually intervene in,
只不过这次你搭档来晚了
except this time your partner was too late.
还是不明白约翰和这件事有什么关系
Still don't understand John's connection to this.
你确定没什么需要告诉我的吗
Are you sure there isn't anything you can tell me?
我确定你自己会查清楚的  警探
I'm sure you'll make sense of it, detective.
你提到说
You were saying something
洁西卡和彼得之间有些问题
about problems between Jessica and Peter.
只是一些小争执
You know, just little spats.
不值一提
Not even worth mentioning.
其中有超过言语范围的争执吗
Do you know if these spats ever went beyond words?
我不知道你是什么意思
I'm not sure what you mean.
他们动过手吗
Did they become physical?
你在暗示什么
What is it you're suggesting?
没什么
Nothing.
只是些常规问题
Just some routine questions.
我得走了
I should get going.
很抱歉打扰您
I'm sorry for troubling you.
彼得是有缺点  但他爱洁西卡
Peter had his faults, but he loved Jessica.
洁西卡也爱他
And she loved him.
我相信她爱他  夫人
I'm sure she did, ma'am.
他远远好过她  之前的男友
He was so much better than her...usual type.
她在彼得之前有别的男友吗
She was seeing someone before Peter?
她和一名士兵有过一段
She had a fling with a soldier.
在她还住在塔克马的时候
Back when she was living in Tacoma.
那名士兵  你记得他的名字吗
This soldier--do you remember his name?
不记得
No.
他们在一起很长时间
They weren't together very long.
他总在执行公务  留下她一个人
He was always away on duty, and then she'd be alone.
她的生活不应该那样
That wasn't the life for her.
他跟她说了同样的话  让她别等他
He told her the same thing-- told her not to wait for him.
不过  我有时想  如果她等了他
However, sometimes I now wonder...if she had waited for him,
也许会更好  也许她现在会很快乐
maybe things could have worked out, maybe she would be happy.
我们现在还能聊天
And we'd talk again.
请问一下  你有那个人的照片吗
Can I ask, do you have any pictures of this man?
没有
I don't.
不过我有些洁西卡的遗物
But I still have some of Jessica's things.
你愿意的话可以看看
You're welcome to look through them if you like.
好的
Sure.
洁西卡
Jessica.
是的  我订婚了
Yeah. I got engaged.
他叫彼得
His name's Peter.
这是你在那边学到的东西
That's one of the things you learn over there.
到头来  我们都是一个人
In the end, we're all alone.
没有人会来救你
And no one's coming to save you.
祝你和彼得幸福
Be happy with Peter.
你不是真心的
You don't believe that?
让我等你  只要你说我就答应
Tell me to wait for you and...say those words and I will.
干杯
Cheers.
到头来  我们都是一个人
In the end, we're all alone.
没有人会来救你
And no one's coming to save you.
基恩
Gene?
我是乔丝・卡特
Joss Carter.
挺好
Good.
帮我个忙
Listen, I need a favor.
个人档案  名字是约翰
Personnel file-- first name John.
特种部队
Special Forces.
在01年六月至九月间
Stationed at Fort Lewis
驻扎在路易斯堡
between June and September of '01.
别让其他人看到
My eyes only.
好的  谢了  基恩
Yeah, thanks, Gene.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
怎么了  芬奇
What is it, Finch?
你抓到詹宁斯警官后打算如何
What exactly is your plan once you catch up to Deputy Jennings?
把萨拉从他身边救走
To get Sarah away from him.
那詹宁斯呢
And Jennings?
我给过詹宁斯机会
Jennings had his chance.
他冥顽不灵
He didn't take it.
我认为此情况下
I think, under the circumstances,
明智的选择是让警察介入此事
it might be a good idea to bring the police in on this one.
芬奇  你雇我来解决这些事情
Finch, you hired me to take care of these things.
如果你不喜欢我的风格  雇别人去
You don't like how I do it, hire someone else.
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese?
约翰
John?
-我是卡特  -你好  警探
- Carter. - Hello, detective.
新罗歇尔这件事
This New Rochelle business--
车祸  掩盖事故  洁西卡
The car accident, the cover up, Jessica.
你知道我会发现什么  对吗
You knew what I'd find, didn't you?
有时知道也不是件好事  警探
Knowing isn't always a blessing, detective.
确实
True.
但我承认我打电话是为更要紧的事  约翰
But, I confess, I was calling with a more urgent problem-- John.
别告诉我你又把他丢了
Don't tell me you've lost him again.
不  我知道他在哪  但我  无法联系他
No, I know where he is. I just... can't reach him.
无法阻止他
Or stop him.
我们来这儿干嘛  布拉德
Why are we here, Brad?
我想跟你好好聚聚  宝贝
I wanted us to have some time together, baby.
就你和我
Just you and me.
我不知道我们之间是怎么变成这样的
I don't know how things got so out of hand with us.
但我保证  我会处理好的
But, I promise, I'm going to fix it.
你不用再逃跑了
You don't have to run anymore.
你相信我  对吗
You believe me... right?
我相信
I do.
我当然相信你  我当然相信
I do believe you, I do believe--
那我们先把手铐摘了吧
So maybe we can take these off now?
你永远学不会说话  是吗
You never did know what to say, did you?
我知道你怎么想的
I know what you're thinking.
你认为都是我的错
That this is my fault.
好像我想这样似的
That, somehow, I wanted this.
但你想过这对我来说有多难吗
But have you ever considered how hard this has been for me?
为你我惹了多大的麻烦
The trouble I've gone through for you?
还要我再付出多少代价  萨拉
What's it gonna take, Sarah?
我非常爱你
I love you so much.
但我不能再继续下去了
But I can't do this anymore.
走
Go.
去哪
Where?
想去哪去哪
Anywhere you want.
你自由了
You're free.
谢谢
Thank you.
萨拉
Sarah.
她走了  结束了
She's gone. It's over.
有什么好笑的
Something funny?
你从没爱过  是吗
You've never been in love, have you?
真正的爱
Really, truly in love?
怎么说
Why?
爱过就会明白  它永远不会结束
Because then you'd know... It'll never be over.
你会结束
It is for you.
你朋友告诉我  或许能在这里找到你
Your friend told me I might find you up this way.
我不能让你带走他  约翰
I can't let you take him, John.
不能重复新罗歇尔的结局
This can't end like New Rochelle.
我需要查看一下后车箱吗
Do I need to look in the trunk?
想做什么随便你
You can do whatever you like.
我要做的事一定会做
It isn't gonna change what I have to do.
把他交给我  约翰
Let me have him, John.
如果我交了  他会脱身
If I do, he'll get away with it.
我保证他不能
I'll see that he doesn't.
那不是你能决定的
It won't be up to you.
这才是重点
That's my point.
有些事你能行  警探  但有些你无能为力
There are things you can do, detective, and things you can't.
所以才需要我的存在
And that's where I come in.
我不能任由你杀人
I can't allow you to just execute people.
这与你无关
This isn't on you.
是我的事
It's on me.
我只要求你相信我
All I'm asking for is your trust.
相信什么
What?
相信你会做正确之事吗
For you to do the right thing?
相信我会做应做之事
That I'll do what needs to be done.
沙利文派你来的吗
Sullivan send you?
这算是在  恐吓我吗
This supposed to be some kind of... intimidation?
我没有钱给他
I don't have his money.
你没有什么我想要的
You don't have anything I want.
已经没有了
Not anymore.
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
问得好
Good question.
我也很久没有答案了
Haven't known the answer for a long time.
我知道我曾是谁
I know who I was.
我曾是那个抛弃她的人
I was the guy who left her behind.
知道为什么吗
You know why?
知道真正的原因吗
The real reason?
因为我认为她值得拥有比我更好的人
Because I thought she deserved someone better than me.
我认为她值得拥有会照顾她
I thought she deserved someone who would look after her...
陪着她的人
be there for her.
我认为她值得拥有像你这样的人
I thought she deserved someone like you.
我不知道
So I don't know.
我还希望你告诉我呢
I was hoping you could tell me.
告诉你什么
Tell you what?
我现在该是谁
Who I'm supposed to be now.
她已经不在了
Now that she's gone.
知道吗
See...
当你找到你在这个世上的羁绊
when you find that one person who connects you to the world,
你就变了
You become someone different...
变得更好
Someone better.
而当她被人从你身边夺去
When that person is taken from you...
那你又会变成怎样
What do you become then?
我都开始琢磨
I was beginning to wonder
几时才能再收到你的信息了
when I was going to hear from you again.
我在城外有点事情要打理
I had some business to take care of, out of town.
相信你现在理解了
I trust you now fully appreciate
我为何不告诉你萨拉一事
why I couldn't tell you about Sarah's case.
希望你现在明白了
I hope you now understand
你为何应该告诉
why you should have.
你早知道了吗
Did you know?
她就是不停跳出来的号码之一吗
Was she one of those numbers that came up again and again?
我只知道  里瑟先生
What I know, Mr. Reese...
新罗歇尔之事
Is that New Rochelle happened
发生在我们共事之前
before we started working together.
正因如此
And because of that,
我们两人对此都是无能为力
there was nothing that either one of us could have done.
忘记把这个放进你的生日礼物里了
Forgot to include that in your birthday present.
肯定是一时疏忽
Must have slipped my mind.
哈罗德・冉
环球人寿保险
巴克斯特街810号
公寓5A
如你所求 吉恩
你好
Hello?
卡特警探吗
Detective Carter?
我是古斯塔沃・佩纳监狱官
This is Warden Gustavo Pena.
这里是墨西哥托雷翁市监狱
I'm calling from Torreon Penitentiary.
有什么事
Yes?
有人让我通知你  我们已经拘捕了你的逃犯
I have been asked to inform you we have your fugitive in custody.
我的逃犯
My fugitive?
是的
Yes.
一个叫詹宁斯的法警送来的
A Marshal Jennings delivered him to us,
在他身上发现了十公斤海洛因
along with ten kilos of uncut heroin found in his possession.
这名法警  我确认一下
This marshal-- just so I'm clear
他是不是高个子  深发色  穿西装
Was he tall, dark hair, in a suit?
是的
That's him.
他说你是最初逮捕那逃犯的警官
He said you were the original arresting officer
让我通知你我们已经将他关押了
and informed me to tell you that we have him in custody.
他得在这里把牢底坐穿
He's going to be here for a long time.
谢谢  监狱官
Thank you, warden.
还有一件事
One other thing.
你那边还关了别的美国人吗
Do you have any other Americans in your prison?
一两个吧
One or two.
谢谢
Thanks.
2011年2月
洁西卡死于一场车祸
Jessica died in a car accident.
对不起
Sorry.
真的对不起
I'm so sorry.
《疑犯追踪》 第1季 第21集
Person of Interest S01E21 720p HDTV x264
-= 人人字幕 =-